The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
♪ Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano ♪
The dreams I see are my secret
♪ Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano ♪
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
♪ Akai manto hira hira ♪
A red cape fluttering
♪ Uma o tobasu oujo ♪
Galloping on a horse—the princess
♪ Sore ga atashi ♪
That’s me!
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Ribon no kishi wa ♪
The Knight of the Ribbon,
♪ Honto wa hontto wa ♪
Truly, truly,
♪ Atashi nano sa ♪
It’s really me!
Twenty-Fifth Episode
The King's Ghost
Banzai for the King!!
Before we start today's story, let's recap what happened last week.
With the King missing and presumed dead,
Sapphire succeeded him to the throne.
However, the villainous Duralumin and Nylon schemed to reveal that
Sapphire is actually a girl...
...was exposed, and she was locked away
in terrifying Coffin Tower along with the Queen.
But the spirited Sapphire didn't back down.
She escaped through the hole the mice showed her
and became the mysterious Ribbon Knight, to punish Duralumin!
However, Duralumin suspected the Ribbon Knight was
Sapphire and sent an assassin to the Coffin Tower,
but they were easily driven off.
But the relentless Duralumin won't give up.
This time, they bribe Gama,
the wicked jailer of the Coffin Tower, to catch Sapphire off guard.
Outside, a fierce storm rages with thunder and lightning.
Today's story begins just as Gama is about to attack Sapphire.
Gama!
Thank you.
You saved Sapphire's life, didn't you?
What's wrong, Sapphire?
Mother, Gama is knocked out cold.
Oh dear, we must tend to him right away.
But what on earth did Gama do to you?
Oh, nothing really.
No?
He wasn't trying to take your life?
Look, he's holding a dagger.
Yeah, he probably got scared by a mouse and
slipped trying to chase it off with his dagger.
Quick, if we don't treat him, he'll die.
He'll be fine now. I'm sure he'll recover.
I'll go boil some more water.
Mother, I'll help you.
You fool!
Do it again!
Their guard is down this time, so make sure you finish them off.
Failure will not be tolerated.
Come on, I'll strike from behind, too.
There we go, Mother.
Thank you.
C-Curse you, intruder!
Gama, you saved us, didn't you?
Gama, thank you, thank you so much!
Thank you so very much.
Ouch!
Ouch! It hurts!
Here.
Here, look.
Hey Gama, mice are really cute, aren't they?
Yeah, they really are cute.
Thanks for the meal.
Well, I'm off!
Why, if it isn't the Ribbon Knight.
I'm not picking on Princess Sapphire anymore, I swear!
It's true! I really have become a loyal servant to Princess Sapphire and the Queen.
Oh, so that's how it was.
Yeah, that's how it was.
The enemies of the Ribbon Knight are that centipede Duralumin and Nylon.
To take those two down, I'd even break into the castle.
What a terrifying princess.
Speaking of the castle, have you heard that rumor?
A rumor?
They say that in the dead of night, the ghost of the late king appears.
My father's ghost?
Anyone who says they saw the ghost
or spreads rumors about it is sent to the quarry as a slave.
Then if I go to the quarry, I can find out more about Father's ghost.
That's the entrance to the quarry.
Security is pretty tight.
Open up!
Now's my chance.
Close it!
Hey you!
Hurry and close it!
Pardon me, but I'm coming through!
Damn it!
Take that!
Cut them down!
Take your work more seriously!
My throat's parched!
I wish the Ribbon Knight would show up here, too.
Ribbon Knight...
Don't be ridiculous, Ribbon Knight.
That's just a children's fantasy, a dream. There's no way he exists.
Reality is much harsher.
We'll just end up drying up in the sun out here.
Water?! No, it's impossible!
Reality is something else!
This is probably just an illusion too.
Why?
Who splashed water on me?
Water! It's water!
It's real water!
Hey, how dare you steal our water!
Stop!
Stop picking on the weak!
That kid... Could it be the Ribbon Knight?
Where are you hiding?
Come out!
Ribbon Knight!
Don't let him get away!
Come on, let's get him!
Alright!
In return, unchain everyone!
Uranari!
Garigori!
Nanny!
How do you know our names...?
P-Princess Sapphire!
Prince Sapphire!
I'm so happy that you are safe!
Come on, hurry up!
Wait, before that, there's something I want to ask.
About my father's ghost.
I've heard about that.
Anyone who heard the King's voice or spread rumors was sent here.
They heard his voice and footsteps?
So nobody actually saw him?
That's right.
No one has actually seen him.
Every night around midnight, the King's voice and footsteps come from the basement...
...from the basement...
It's about time the King's ghost starts walking around down there...
It's almost time...
Under the lion ornament, the third stone...
One, two, three...
This is it!
Here we go...
It's the tomb...
It's midnight...
Father's voice...
Father...
Father!
Who's there?
You're alive?
Father...
Is that you, Sapphire...?
So you survived as well...
Father, Mother is safe and well, too...
I see. I missed you...
But who could it be?
Who trapped you in a place like this?
I don't know.
I couldn't see what they looked like at all.
That night—the night I was attacked—
I was in my room writing an important decree.
Thrown into this dungeon by an unknown enemy,
I was trapped for six days without any food or water.
So the enemy intended to starve you to death, Father.
There is something even more important than that...
What is it?
If only I could retrieve the decree I wrote that night...
Wasn't it burned?
However, I wrote that on tanned leather,
so it might have survived the fire. Sapphire, could you go fetch it?
Yes.
He really got us good!
It's the Ribbon Knight!
What?
The Ribbon Knight?
Are you talking in your sleep?
Security is far too strict for anyone to get in.
You idiot!
Found it!
Something is shining right here!
It's too dark to see.
You're in the way!
Pardon me!
Lend me some light!
Can you tell what it says?
Don't worry, I can read it clearly.
Thank you very much!
Don't mention it.
Grand Duke Duralumin!
Please read this.
Anyway, these flyers are pasted all over town.
"Gather in front of the castle gates at 10 a.m. today, Ribbon Knight..."
What if something bad happens!
Don't be stupid!
You'll see something interesting!
What should we do?
Drive them off!
Shoot yourself at them or fire the cannons, just drive them off!
But there are way too many of them! We can't do a thing!
What are you trying to do?!
Everyone, there is someone I want you to see!
Duralumin!
Nylon!
Take a good look!
The Queen?! How did she escape from the Coffin Tower... wait, what?!
N-No way... But...
The King is alive!
I was trapped in the castle dungeon by someone and nearly killed.
Regrettably, I don't know who was behind it.
But I survived and was rescued.
Thanks to the Ribbon Knight.
Come, Father. Let's go inside the castle.
You cannot enter.
You are no longer the King.
Plastic is the King now.
Silence, Duralumin!
This castle belongs to me and my heir, Sapphire!
Heir, you say?
Everyone knows that by Silverland law, a woman cannot be an heir.
Exactly. Until I change that foolish law. And I have changed it.
You can't just change it on a whim.
Not without proof!
The proof is right here.
Official proof stamped with the royal seal.
I wrote this and affixed my seal before I was locked away.
Damn it!
Now, I shall announce the decree changing the law before all our people.
I hereby change the law of Silverland that forbids women from taking the throne!
In the name of the King, I hereby decree that a woman may become queen and rule this land.
Mother!
Hey, Papa, so I don't have to be king anymore?
Fool, shut your mouth!
Really? I'm really not king anymore?
That's right, confound it!
Ooh, that is so cool!
Come, let's step inside.
Curse them! Do they think I will just back down like this?
Princess Sapphire!
Princess, it isn't right for a princess to be dressed like a boy.
Thank you, young lady.
Thank you so much.
But I still want to dress as a boy for now.
I'll stay like this until the evil is gone and true peace comes to this kingdom.
I'll keep this dress safe until then.
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen ♪
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
♪ Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen ♪
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
♪ Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo ♪
Even if demons come, even if storms arrive,
♪ tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai ♪
Our bonded hearts will never part.
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP